Inventory of the Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage Collection, 1883-1939
Hoover Institution Archives
Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage collection
1883-1939
1936-1939
XX529
Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
German antisemitic propaganda, including clippings, leaflets, and posters. Collected by the Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (1 reel).
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Scope and Content of Collection
German antisemitic propaganda, including clippings, leaflets, and posters. Collected by the Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage.
Arrangement
Arranged in two subseries, Collected Material and Publication of the Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage.; Antisemitism--Germany.; Jews--Germany.; National socialism.
Container List
- Collected Material, 1884-1939
  - German anti-Semitic fliers and similar material, 1884-1926; undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - "Aber der Zoll faßte sie doch!" Angriff, 1938 December - 1939 January (Folder 1: 2)
    Clippings
  - "Das Füllhorn des Elends: Deutsche Farmer in Weizengürtel der Prärie," Angriff, 1938 April (Folder 1: 3)
  - "Der hessische Bauer im Kampf um Acker und Hof," Frankfurter Volksblatt, 1936 September-October (Folder 1: 4)
  - Felix Perles, "Die Wanderungen der Juden," Königsberger Jüdisches Gemeindeblatt, 1931 (Folder 1: 5)
    Photostat of article
  - "Das jüdische Verbrechen," Mitteldeutsche, 1938 November (Folder 1: 6)
  - "Dividende vom Tod," Mitteldeutsche, 1938 December (Folder 1: 7)
    Pages from newspaper
  - "Die Macht im Schatten," Schwarze Korps, 1939 March-May (Folder 1: 8)
    Clippings and pages from newspaper
  - Corneliu Zelia Codreanu, "Eiserne Garde," Völkischer Beobachter, 1939 January-February (Folder 1: 9)
  - Wilhelm Ziegler, "Das Ende des Zweiten Reiches," Völkischer Beobachter, 1938 October (Folder 1: 10)
  - "Die geheimnisvolle Million" (Sacerdoti), Völkischer Beobachter, 1938 November (Folder 1: 11)
  - "Jude, wie siehst Du aus?" 12 Uhr Blatt, 1938 November (Folder 1: 12)
- Publication of the Institut zum Studium der Judenfrage, 1939
  - Mitteilungen über die Judenfrage, 1939 November 14 (Folder 1: 13)